<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://peachycian.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://peachycian.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-03T14:41:17+01:00</updated><id>https://peachycian.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">peachycian</title><subtitle>A new blog for design concepts centred around transport, cities, and people.</subtitle><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><entry><title type="html">Consultation: Capel &amp;amp; Parliament St.</title><link href="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/09/03/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consultation: Capel &amp;amp; Parliament St." /><published>2021-09-03T14:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-03T14:30:00+01:00</updated><id>https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/09/03/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/09/03/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st.html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with this trial, I’ll start with a quick recap. If you want to skip to how to fill out the consultation, &lt;a href=&quot;#participate&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st/Parliament-Street-2017.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st/Parliament-Street-2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photograph of Parliament Street on a clear Autumnal day, taken facing southwards from Dublin City Hall. The street has two lanes of motor traffic, both travelling toward the viewer, and is lined with bare deciduous trees. The footpaths appear wide, although there is much street clutter, and parking and loading bays take chunks from the pavement. A van turns to the viewer's left, while a number 79 Dublin Bus destined for the City Centre turns right along with two cars behind it. The street is lined almost entirely with historic four-storied red-brick buildings, mostly in use as restaurants and bars.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Parliament Street as it was in 2017 - motor traffic continues to occupy most of the space on the street today. Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Parliament_Street,_Dublin,_5_September_2017.jpg&quot;&gt;hillofthirst&lt;/a&gt;, CC0, via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-trial-so-far&quot;&gt;The Trial So Far&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the pandemic, Dublin City Council asked the public for places where they would like more space given to active transport - walking, cycling, using mobility aids, scooting, and new transit like e-scooters. The single most requested change, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dublininquirer.com/2021/05/05/here-are-the-transport-changes-2-300-people-asked-for-to-make-the-city-better-for-covid-travel&quot;&gt;with 10% of the overall submissions&lt;/a&gt;, was to make Capel Street car-free. However, the Council’s first proposal was underwhelming - motor traffic remained on the streets, with footpaths widened in only a limited number of places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://janethorner.ie/post/improved-plans-for-partial-pedestrianisation-of-capel-street/&quot;&gt;A public consultation on the plan received over 4,500 responses&lt;/a&gt;, and showed support from a majority of the public, residents, and business owners, with 85% of the public voicing support, and many requesting pedestrianisation. A new proposal was created, which included a car-free trial for 6 weeks in the summer - but only after 6:30pm on Friday, Saturday, and Sunday nights. Given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NickyRyan_/status/1404107932057444356?s=20&quot;&gt;huge success of this trial&lt;/a&gt;, the car-free nights were extended for a further six weeks, after which a public consultation on the scheme was to be held in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DubCityCouncil/status/1429839251542261765?s=20&quot;&gt;the announcement of the end of the trial&lt;/a&gt; towards the end of August resulted in many complaints, the trial was yet again extended to the end of September, continuing during the consultation. This is where we currenly stand.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-whats-the-plan-now&quot;&gt;So, What’s the Plan Now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four general options in the consultation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return to what we had before, with no pedestrianisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return to what we had before, including removing widened footpaths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the trial arrangement permanent, with pedestrianisation after 6:30pm on weekend nights.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the streets pedestrianised 24/7 (with deliveries at set times).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I strongly support the third choice. This would allow a redesign of the streetscapes of Capel and Parliament Streets, without having to design around cars. We could plant trees and other greenery, which would help with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fevo.2021.603757/full?utm_source=S-TWT&amp;amp;utm_medium=SNET&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ECO_FEVO_XXXXXXXX_auto-dlvrit&quot;&gt;pollution, sound dampening, and rainwater absorption.&lt;/a&gt; We could properly set out spaces for people passing though and those dining and drinking, allowing for easier social distancing and easier movement. The clutter of traffic lights and signs can be removed, high kerbs changed to a level and smooth street surface, and street furniture like public benches installed, all of which would make the streets more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/09687599727010?casa_token=XXktafDRMDcAAAAA%3AR9DA2CPVJ-Im3Tw7FjkhiFsFdIfxblslXCevBePpi0XYQwJRwvogWBEEHR_lxGRBRUfUguxukd7Tng&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;accessible to the disabled.&lt;/a&gt; Finally, with no cars, noise and air pollution will be reduced, and the street will be much safer for all, and dining outdoors will just be far more pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the effects on congestion - where will all the displaced motor traffic go? Surprisingly, it just stops existing! People will make trips at different times, or choose to take public or active transport instead, keeping traffic at the same balancing point as before. This phenomenon is often referred to as traffic evaporation, and is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand#Reduced_demand&quot;&gt;extension of induced demand&lt;/a&gt;, a well documented effect. This is why building more roads doesn’t seem to help traffic: it encourages more and more people to drive until that tipping point is reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often point to Irish weather, and speculate if people will be willing to dine outdoors year-round. However, continental cities like Copenhagen, Amsterdam, Brussels, and even Paris have plenty of pedestrianised streets and outdoor dining, and have roughly equivalent levels of rainfall in Winter. In fact, on average Paris actually has a greater number of rainy days than Ireland between October and June!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;participate&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st/Dining-Outdoors-on-Capel-Street.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/consultation-capel-and-parliament-st/Dining-Outdoors-on-Capel-Street.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photograph looking down along rows of tables on Capel Street on a sunny day. To the left, an old wrought iron lamppost, planter boxes and screens separate diners from traffic that's just out of view. To the right, several people walk long the old footpath, and several shops are seen, shutters down. The centre of the picture shows tables with potted plants, hand sanitiser, and soy sauce, all with umbrellas up. Most tables appear to be full.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Outdoor dining on the widened footpaths of Capel Street, still popular despite traffic passing close by. Image: Before the Surge [Dining Outdoors on Capel Street] by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/infomatique/51318715684/&quot;&gt;William Murphy&lt;/a&gt;, CC BY-SA 2.0, via Flickr&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;How to participate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://consultation.dublincity.ie/traffic-and-transport/feedback-on-traffic-free-trial-at-capel-street-par/&quot;&gt;consultation page is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Below a summary of the project there is a link to complete an “online survey” - click this to start the consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be completed in &lt;strong&gt;under 2 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; - to show support you need to click 7 buttons total. &lt;strong&gt;There is only one mandatory question.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve listed the questions I &lt;em&gt;recommend&lt;/em&gt; you give your answer to below in bold. If you would like to support both streets being car-free 24/7, I’ve also made notes of which options support this. However, I’d recommend giving your opinion to as many questions as you’re able. I’ll give some inspiration below the list of questions, and you shouldn’t be shy about copy-pasting your own answers from one section into another if it applies to both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;you should be giving your own opinions here.&lt;/strong&gt; This post is a guide on &lt;em&gt;how to have your say&lt;/em&gt;, not on &lt;em&gt;what to say.&lt;/em&gt; This is an opportunity for you to let the Council know what you think - just be honest!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;page-1&quot;&gt;Page 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Question&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q1. Your contact details&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2. Who you are (mandatory)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Likely a &lt;strong&gt;“Member of the public”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q3. How the trial affected your experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q4. Benefits you saw of the trial&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q5. Issues you saw with the trial&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;page-2&quot;&gt;Page 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Question&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q6. Capel St Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 2&lt;/strong&gt; makes all of Capel St car-free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q7. Your reason for your choice&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q8. When should the street be car-free?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1&lt;/strong&gt; makes Capel St car-free 24/7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;page-3&quot;&gt;Page 3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Question&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q9. Parliament St Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1&lt;/strong&gt; makes Parliament St car-free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q10. Your reason for your choice&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q8. When should the street be car-free?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1&lt;/strong&gt; makes Parliament St car-free 24/7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q10. Any other comments&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Can be about either street&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;page-4&quot;&gt;Page 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Question&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Q- Your email&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Optional, sends you a PDF copy of your choices&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t forget to click all the way to the end and submit your response!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;talking-points&quot;&gt;Talking Points&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some issues that you might have thoughts on include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noise pollution from traffic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air pollution, and the Climate crisis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accessibility
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Moving disabled parking to nearby and sensible locations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Providing public bathrooms and benches&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clearly marking cycle lanes with strong visual contrast &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; tactile paving/kerbs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Removal of street clutter like signs and traffic lights&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a safe environment for children and the elderly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outdoor dining &amp;amp; drinking
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Making the experience better&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Providing more space&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Safety&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bikes, scooters, etc.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Providing a safe corridor through the city&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Maintaining access (not limiting street to only pedestrians)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Parking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pandemic, and social distancing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Art and aesthetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Consultation Guides" /><category term="Active Transport" /><category term="Dublin" /><summary type="html">A guide on how to give your response to the public consultation on continuing the pedestrianisation of Capel Street and Parliament Street. Closing date: 20th September 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Update</title><link href="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/16/first-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Update" /><published>2021-06-16T16:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-16T16:20:00+01:00</updated><id>https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/16/first-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/16/first-update.html">&lt;p&gt;This site is as much an experiment in me learning to code as it is a place to showcase my other work, so documenting my changes here seems worthwhile!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;Tags&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tagging system on the blog is now working! Granted, there’s not much to look at at the minute, but as this site grows I plan to allow users to filter posts to see only what’s relevant to them (be that topic, location, or project based), and to offer RSS feeds for each tag category (more on that in a second). A search feature would also be a nice thing to have, but that’s some ways down the road for now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have implemented commenting on the website, using a (free) Disqus account. I really hope to receive feedback in the future, as I firmly believe that it will result in better work in the long run. Unfortunately, Disqus will probably place some ads on my site - I think for now that it’s still the best solution, but I’ll be looking into other options in the future.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rss-feeds&quot;&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have strong feelings about the direction that the internet has taken in the last few years, with a huge proportion of all web content hosted on non-customisable social media sites run by huge for-profit corporations. RSS is an old-fashioned way of receiving updates from sites you’re interested in, akin to following or subscribing, without the need to create an account on the website. At the minute there’s just one global RSS feed, however I have plans to implement feeds on a tag-by-tag basis as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect RSS, or a modern equivalent, will make a major comeback at some point, as the user-retention focused form the internet has taken strikes me as profoundly unsustainable. How many people &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to use Facebook or Twitter, compared to those who find the experience miserable, but feel obliged to in order to not fall entirely out-of-the-loop? I would guess not many!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-stuff&quot;&gt;Other Stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made a couple of minor design changes, and plan to keep polishing the look and feel of the site as time goes on. If you have a specific request for a change, please do let me know, because I’d be delighted to receive feedback!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, but I’ll be back pretty soon with my post on DART+ Southwest, seeing as that public consultation will be closing soon. See you then!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Maintenance" /><summary type="html">A quick rundown of the new features I've added to this website: tags, comments, and RSS feeds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/06/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2021-06-06T18:33:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-06T18:33:00+01:00</updated><id>https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/06/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peachycian.github.io/blog/2021/06/06/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to my site! I wanted a place to put my ideas and figured a blog format would work best for this task. I’d like to thank Caelen Feller, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PROGRAM_IX&quot;&gt;James Heslin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://renidon.com&quot;&gt;Ren McDonagh&lt;/a&gt; for their help with setting this up (more on that later), and would really encourage you to go check out their work. Ren is one of the most talented designers I’ve ever seen, and James is a veritable renaissance man. Caelen has less of a public internet presence, but she’s a wonderful and wickedly smart person.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m hoping this site will allow me to showcase my design work, which will push me to complete more of it instead of calling it quits at the final stretch. I generally work on transportation and urban design projects, but I also have many, many other interests - a list of the things I hope to work on can be found in the “About” page for now. I don’t have a planned schedule, for releasing things here, other than “when they’re finished”, so check &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peachycian&quot;&gt;my twitter&lt;/a&gt; for updates for now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This site is obviously still in its infancy, so there’s definitely some unpolished edges. I chose the hardest possible option because I decided learning to code would be interesting - it was, but the friends I consulted with also suggested a lot of easier options, which I really appreciated. If you’re curious, the website is (as of posting) entirely free: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/01-setup/&quot;&gt;Jekyll site&lt;/a&gt;, using a tweaked version of the default Minima theme, hosted on GitHub. I really can’t recommend the step-by-step tutorial linked above enough if you’re curious about setting one up yourself.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There’s no time like the present, so I’ll continue adding features to the site alongside beginning to post content. My current priorities are implementing accessibility features, search, and a more straightforward workflow for updates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That’s all for now, thanks for reading, and I hope to see you around when this project is complete!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Maintenance" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">A welcome to this website, an idea of what I'll be posting, and when I'll be posting it.</summary></entry></feed>