<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-06T19:41:47+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">peachycian</title><subtitle>A new blog for design concepts centred around transport, cities, and people.</subtitle><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="/blog/2021/06/06/my-first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2021-06-06T18:33:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-06T18:33:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/06/06/my-first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/06/06/my-first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to my site! I wanted a place to put my ideas and figured a blog format would work best for this task. I’d like to thank Caelen Feller, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PROGRAM_IX&quot;&gt;James Heslin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://renidon.com&quot;&gt;Ren McDonagh&lt;/a&gt; for their help with setting this up (more on that later), and would really encourage you to go check out their work. Ren is one of the most talented designers I’ve ever seen, and James is a veritable renaissance man. Caelen has less of a public internet presence, but is a wonderful and wickedly smart person.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m hoping this site will allow me to showcase my design work, which will push me to complete more of it instead of calling it quits at the final stretch. I generally work on transportation and urban design projects, but I also have many, many other interests - a list of the things I hope to work on can be found in the “About” page for now. I don’t have a planned schedule, for releasing things here, other than “when they’re finished”, so check &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peachycian&quot;&gt;my twitter&lt;/a&gt; for updates for now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This site is obviously still in its infancy, so there’s definitely some unpolished edges. I chose the hardest possible option because I decided learning to code would be interesting - it was, but the friends I consulted with also suggested a lot of easier options, which I really appreciated. If you’re curious, the website is (as of posting) entirely free: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/01-setup/&quot;&gt;Jekyll site&lt;/a&gt;, using a tweaked version of the default Minima theme, hosted on GitHub. I really can’t recommend the step-by-step tutorial linked above enough if you’re curious about setting one up yourself.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There’s no time like the present, so I’ll continue adding features to the site alongside beginning to post content. My current priorities are implementing accessibility features, search, and a more straightforward workflow for updates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That’s all for now, thanks for reading, and I hope to see you around when this project is complete!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cian Murphy</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Maintenance" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">A Welcome to this website, what I'll be posting, and when I'll be posting it.</summary></entry></feed>